<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
	<!-- Here are the default/english translations for the app. If the phones language isn't supported, it will show english by default-->
    
	<string name="manappvs" translatable="false">1.0.8</string>
		
	<string name="otsikko">MCPEinfo</string>
    <string name="app_name">MCPEinfo</string>
	<string name="exit">Exit app</string>
	<string name="introduction">Introduction</string>
	<string name="basic">Basics</string>
	<string name="secret">Commands</string>
	<string name="cmd">Write changelog in command screen to see the changelog\n\nWrite upcoming in command screen to see upcoming stuff</string>
	<string name="cmdline">Enter command</string>
	<string name="enter">Enter</string>
	<string name="clog">Changelog</string>
	
	<string name="changes">1.0.8\n\nMade some changes to the Feedback section.\nFixed a bad bug with the tutorial section where the app chrashed because of high image resolutions.\nStarted implementing Material Design for Android 5.0 Lollipop (API level 21)and trying to and some material design for API levels 14 and higher.\nCleaned app code\nAdded more comments\nNow the app detects the devices API level and opens an activity depending on that. Though at the moment the user won't notice a difference because there's nothing special added to take use of that feature\nPartial German translations thanks to ChrisMcMine\nIf the user is running Android 5.0 on their device, they can now see that on-screen navigation buttons change color and the toolbar and statusbar have a new color too.\n\n\n1.0.75\n\nUpdated the bug reporting section.\nIt\'s no longer required for the user to manually input their Android version, since the app collects the information automatically.\nUpdated app rating section.\nYou can now select to rate the app on Google Play or by using the old method(Email).\nThe app should now work correctly with all Android versions with API level 8 or later.\nUsers can now translate the app in to their native language using the link found in the app description in Google Play store.\n\n\n1.0.74\n\nUpdated the bug reporting section.\nRemoved some secret commands.\nRemoved some pictures and sound files that weren\'t used.\nChanged app backgrounds in vertical and horizontal modes.\n\n\n1.0.73\n\nPossibly fixed the \"About app\" screen on small screens.\nThe main menu now looks better on smaller screens.\nFixed a bug.\n\n\n1.0.72\n\nFixed a bug where a finnish translation wouldn\'t show at all.\nMade a few changes to the code.\n\n\n1.0.71\n\nChanged some app signing stuff.\nWhen the \"Send\" button is pressed in the Feedback section, the keyboard is now automatically been hidden (Depending on your email app, the keyboard may be re-opened when the email app gets launched).\nImproved the way the app version is obtained.\nImages should no longer have empty space below, or above them.\nThe Feedback section of the app should now be bug free.\nAdjusted some buttons to be more sensible.\n\n\n1.0.7\n\nChanged the font to look more like the Minecraft font.\nAdjusted picture sizes.\nChanged a couple of secret commands.\nAdded a crafting and furnace tutorial.\nReduced app size by a fair bit.\nUpdated the \"upcoming\" screen.\nUpdated the About app screen.\nFixed bugs.\nMade the code easier to read.\nImproved the code.\nUpdated the Feedback section.\nMade the app easier to update (end users won\'t notice any difference)\nMade the email sending better.\n\n\n1.0.6\n\nAdded new command(can be found from the main menu).\nAdded new backgrounds for both landscape and portrait mode.\nImproved the app code.\nAdded information as comments in to the source.\nFinished everything in the Main Menu and Settings section.\nAdded a new secret command.\nAdded new sounds.\n\n\n1.0.52\n\nImproved the Feedback section\n\n\n1.0.51\n\nFixed bug where you couldn\'t view the 1.0.5 changelog in finnish.\nImproved text in some parts of the app.\n\n\n1.0.5\n\nChanged the Main Menu a bit.\nAdded an introduction to the app.\nAdded Something to the Basics section of the app.\nImproved a few things with the music in some parts of the app.\nImproved the app code.\n\n\n1.0.48\n\nChanged music in the main menu.\nAdded music to changelog.\n\n\n1.0.47\n\nNew app icon.\n\n\n1.0.46b\n\nFixed a critical bug with the feedback section, it now works in landscape mode.\n\n\n1.0.46\n\nImproved Multi-Window support a lot, it should now work without any problems.\nMain menu works in a different way.\nThe whole app works in landscape now.\n\n\n1.0.45\n\nFixed an issue with viewing text in changelog while in landscape mode.\n\nImproved support for Samsungs Multi-Window feature, works best in command screen and changelog.\n\n\n1.0.44\n\nChangelog now works in landscape mode\n\n\n1.0.43\n\nImproved command screen to work in landscape mode.\n\n\n1.0.42\n\nThe command screen can be used in landscape mode again.\n\n1.0.41\n\nAdded more details to the homescreen.\nMade the app portrait-only for now, but that might change.\n\n\n1.0.4\n\nMade sending feedback easier.\nFixed a bug.\n\n\n1.0.32\n\nMore bugfixes.\nFixen screen orientation issue in certain cases.\n\n\n1.0.31\n\nFixed bugs.\nFixed issues with the main menu.\n\n\n1.0.3\n\nAdded possibility to send feedback via email.\n\n\n1.0.21\n\nSmall bugfix.\n\n\n1.0.2\n\nAdded a secret command.\nImproved changelog and command screen.\nAdded new sound files.\n\n\n1.0.1\n\nCleaned app code.\nMade app faster.\nAdded commands.\n\n\n1.0\n\nFirst release.</string>
	
	<string name="note">NOTE!\nThe commands are case-sensitive!</string>
	<string name="feedbackmenu">Feedback</string>
	
	<string name="betanote"><!--NOTE:\nThis is a beta version so it might be unstable and possibly contains some bugs!\n--></string>
	
	<string name="aboutapp">App developer:\nChris Mustola(Bettehem)\n\n\nThe app has been tested on following Android versions:\n<!--\n2.3.3\n2.3.6-->\n4.1.2\n4.2.2\n4.3\n4.4.2\n\n\nMulti-Window feature tested on following devices:\n\nSamsung Galaxy S3\nSamsung Galaxy S4\nSamsung Galaxy Note 10.1\n\n\nApp icon and backround creator:\nSami Pietilä (xFinL4x)\n\nMusic by HardPaw\n\nSome help with translations in version 1.0.7: Aleksi Hakala</string>
	<string name="abouttext">About app</string>
	
	
	<string name="version">App version:</string>
	
	
	<string name="upcoming">MCPE 0.9.0 is coming out soon. It\'s currently in the beta testing stage, so this will be the last update on 0.8.x versions. I\'ll start focusing on 0.9.0 now. The update is huge, and I have a lot to do. More on this soon..</string>

	
	<string name="bugs">Report a bug</string>
	<string name="rating">Rate</string>
	<string name="other">Other</string>
	<string name="itext">Welcome to MCPEinfo.\nThis App will give you up-to-date information about MCPE.\nYou will be able to learn everything from the very basics to advanced things.\nGo to the Basics section in the main menu to get started.\nThis app will not have ads, ever. And it will be totally free! Have fun!</string>
	<string name="gotob">Go to Basics</string>
	<string name="basictxt">Welcome to learn basics of MCPE</string>
	<string name="menut">Main menu and Settings</string>
	<string name="msettings076">Main Menu and Settings.\n\nWhen you launch MCPE, you will get something like this:\n(Since 0.7.6, the realms button hasn\'t been visible in the main menu)</string>
	<string name="msettings2_076">This is the Main Menu. Below the header, there are two buttons, Play and Play on Realms. Also, in the bottom right corner, there is a button that opens the Settings.\nTap the Play, Play on Realms, or Settings button to see what they do.</string>
	<string name="playmenutxt">This is what you will see when you tap on the Play button.\nIf you already have created worlds, you would see them here.\nTo create a new world, tap on New, and you should see something like this:</string>
	<string name="playmenutxt2">Here you would have to give your world a name. Then you can type something in the seed box. You can also leave it blank for a random seed. Then, on the right side of the screen, you can select what gametype you want it to be: Creative or Survival. And when you are done, tap on the Generate World -button.\n\n\nSince 0.7.4, it has been possible to join external servers straight from the app. To do this, tap on the Edit button in the Play menu, and then tap on External. You should see something like this:</string>
	<string name="playmenutxt3">At first, you can name the server anything you want. Then, in to the second box, you should type the server IP. And in to the last box, goes the server port, and usually that is 19132. And when everything is done, tap the Add Server button.</string>
	<string name="openpic">Open the picture</string>
	<string name="backbtn">Go back</string>
	<string name="realmstxt">At the moment, Realms is in a testing stage, and available to only a few people. When it\'s out for everyone, there will be more information here.</string>
	<string name="settingstxt">To get in to the games settings from the main menu, tap the button at the bottom right corner of the screen (tool icon).\nYou can also get to the settings in-game by tapping the back key or the menu key an then Options.\nThere are 4 sections in the settings:\nGame, Controls, Graphics and Sound.\n\nTap the buttons below to see what you can do with the settings.\n\n</string>
	<string name="gamesettings">In the Game settings, you can see 4 options: Name, Difficulty, Third person view and Local server multiplayer. With the Name option, you can change your name. This is not possible if you have logged on to realms and your name will appear in grey.\n\nThe Difficulty option allows you to change the gamemode between peaceful (button at the left) and normal (Might be easy, not so sure.)(button at the right).\n\nThird person view let\'s you change your camera angle from first person, to third person.\n\nWith the Local server multiplayer option you can change the visibility of your game to other players on the same wifi.</string>
	<string name="graphicsettings">In the Graphics settings, you can see 6 options: View Distance, Fancy Graphics, Beautiful skies, Animated water, Smooth lighting and Hide GUI(GUI stands for Graphical User Interface). With the View Distance option you can change the view distance in the game. Use a low view distance if you have an old device, since a high view distance will make the game lag and maybe even crash. With the Fancy Graphics option turned on, your game will look better, for example, leaves will become transparent. Again, This isn\'t recommended for an old device. Beautiful skies option allows you to have the sun, moon, stars and clouds in the game. Use only on a mid-range or a high-end device. Animated water option gives a flowing animation to the water. Experimental options may not work very well on some devices and might make the game crash. Use with caution. Smooth lighting makes the shadows in the game very smooth, but for some reason the game looks darker with this option turned on. Hide GUI option hides the in-game graphical user interface, and that means the d-pad, the hotbar and the chat button. This is good for taking sreenshots.</string>
	<string name="ctrlsettings">In the Controls settings, you can see 6 options: Sensitivity, Invert Y-Axis, Lefty, Split controls, D-Pad size and Destroy block (vibrate). With the Sensitivity option you can adjust the camera turning sensitivity by usind the slider. With the Invert Y-Axis option you can invert the vertical turning of the camera. So when you slide your finger up, the camera will turn down and vice versa. With the Lefty option you can move the D-pad to the right side of the screen. This feels more natural for some players. With the Split controls option you can get a pointer on to the screen, just like the PC and Xbox version has. With the D-Pad size option you can adjust the size of the D-pad. By making it small, more hotbar slots will become available. With the Destroy block (vibrate) option you can choose if you want to make your device vibrate a bit when you destroy a block.</string>
	<string name="soundsettings">In the Sound settings, you can see 1 option: Sound Volume. With this option you can adjust, how loud all of the sounds are in the game.</string>
	<string name="oldversions">(If you want to see this section for older MCPE versions, write oldbasics in the command screen)</string>
	<string name="selectold">Select a version</string>
	<string name="msettings080">Main Menu and Settings.\n\nWhen you launch MCPE, you will get something like this:\n</string>
	<string name="msettings2_080">This is the Main Menu. Below the header, there is one button, Play. Also, in the bottom right corner, there is a button that opens the Settings.\nTap the Play or Settings button to see what they do.\n\nAlso, in the bottom left corner you can see the version of MCPE you are running.</string>
	<string name="appsettings">Settings</string>
	<string name="musicsettings">App Music</string>
	<string name="musicsetinfo">Turn music on or off</string>
	<string name="crash">App Crashed</string>
	<string name="nocmderror">ERROR!\nThat commmand doesn\'t exist</string>
	<string name="nocmdtexterror">ERROR!\nType something first!</string>
	<string name="crashrep">What did you do that caused the app to crash?</string>
	<string name="buganswer">Type your answer here</string>
	<string name="androidversion">What is your Android version?</string>
	<string name="androidversionanswer">Type your Android version here, for example \"4.1.2\"</string>
	<string name="extracomment">Type an extra comment(Optional)</string>
	<string name="extracommentanswer">Type something!</string>
	<string name="taptosend">Tap the button below to send this feedback.\nYour email will open. Then just send the email.</string>
	<string name="taptosendrating">Tap the button below to send this rating.\nYour email will open. Then just send the email.</string>
	<string name="sendbtn">SEND</string>
	<string name="nomodify">DO NOT MODIFY THIS MESSAGE\nIf the message has content that is not sensible, the whole message will be ignored.\n\n</string>
	<string name="crashrepsub">MCPEinfo Crash Report for </string>
	<string name="gfxbug">Graphical Bug</string>
	<string name="gfxrep">How did you find this bug and where?</string>
	<string name="gfxbugsub">MCPEinfo Graphical Bug Report for </string>
	<string name="giverating">Rate this app</string>
	<string name="ratingsub">MCPEinfo Rating for </string>
	<string name="selectotherfbsub">Select subject</string>
	<string name="featuresug">Suggest a new feature</string>
	<string name="moresoon">More coming soon</string>
	<string name="selectsubfirst">Select a subject first</string>
	<string name="typemsghere">Type your message here</string>
	<string name="thanksforfb">Thanks for your feedback!</string>
	<string name="typesomethingfirst">Type something first!</string>
	<string name="allcommands">All of the existing commands</string>
	<string name="craftingtutorial">Crafting</string>
	<string name="craftingintro">In this section of MCPEinfo, you will learn how to use the crafting interface in MCPE.\n\nYou can use the crafting interface in survival mode only. The system works very differently compared to the PC version, but is a bit similar to the console version of Minecraft.\nThere is a crafting menu that you can acces through your inventory. To open your inventory, tap the icon with three dots[...]:</string>
	<string name="craftingintro2">...and you should see something like this:</string>
	<string name="craftingintro3">In the upper right part of the screen, there are two buttons: Craft and Armor.\nTap on the \"Craft\" button to open the crafting menu.\nTap on the button below to learn how to use the crafting interface.\n</string>
	<string name="learnhowtocraft">Learn how to use the crafting interface</string>
	<string name="usingcraftui">Using the crafting interface</string>
	<string name="howtocraft_text080">Now you wil learn how to use the crafting interface. It has been made quite simple in MCPE, since you don\'t need to remember the crafting recipes at all.\nSo, let\'s get started!\n\nOnce you have your crafting screen open, you should be able to see something like this:\n</string>
	<string name="howtocraft_text2080">At the left side of the screen, you can see 4 icons, and when you tap on one of them, the corresponding menu will appear. In the middle of the screen, you can see all of the items you can craft, and they are organized alphabetically. If you have items in your inventory, that you can use to craft something, those crafting recipes will appear on the top of the list. At the right side of the screen, you can see what items are required to craft the selected item. It will also show you the amount of the required items you have in your inventory, and below that, is a description for the item. For example in the picture above, I have a bunch of cobblestone in my inventory, so the recipe for the stonecutter will appear at the top of my list. At the right side of the screen, you can see that the stonecutter requires 4 cobblestone to be crafted, and i have over 99. To craft an item, tap on the box at the right side of the screen, and the item will be crafted. To acces all of the crafting recipes, you will have to make a crafting table, which requires 4 wooden planks. Here\'s what a crafting table looks like:\n</string>
	<string name="howtocraft_text3080">And to craft all of the stone-related blocks, you will have to make a stonecutter. A stonecutters interface works in the same way as a normal crafting interface, so nothing special over there.</string>
	<string name="furnacetutorial">Furnace</string>
	<string name="furnaceintro080">In this section of MCPEinfo, you will learn how to use the furnace in MCPE.\n\nYou can use the furnace in survival mode only. The furnace interface works pretty similarly compared to the PC and Console edition, so if you have used those, this will be quite easy.\nTo build a furnace, you need 8 cobblestone. The furnace recipe is only available through the crafting table.</string>
	<string name="taptolearncraft">Tap this button to learn how to craft</string>
	<string name="furnaceintro2080">Now that you have a furnace built, we can move on to the next step.\nTap the button below to learn how to use the furnaces interface.</string>
	<string name="howtosmelt">Learn how to use the furnace</string>
	<string name="usingfurnace">Using the furnace</string>
	<string name="howtosmelt_text080">To use a furnace tap on it(has to be placed on the ground), or if you have split touch controls enabled, as in the picture below, just point the crosshair at the furnace and tap the screen.</string>
	<string name="howtosmelt_text2080">An interface for the furnace should open.</string>
	<string name="howtosmelt_text3080">On the left side of the screen you can see all of the blocks that you can use with the furnace. On the right side of the screen, there are three boxes. The box at the very right edge of the screen, is the \"output\", here all of the smelted or cooked items will appear when the process is complete. The other two boxes, that are placed on top of each other, is where all of the magic happens. The box at the bottom, is where the fuel goes. When the box is selected(tap to select a box), in the inventory, all of the available fuel gets highlighted, an now you can select the fuel that you want to use, by tapping on the fuel. Fuel can basically be anything that\'s made of wood, including sticks, stairs, bookshelves etc.\nYou can also use coal, charcoal(made by burning/smelting wood in a furnace), and buckets filled with lava. If you select the upper box, you can place in whatever you want to cook or smelt. If you already have some fuel placed, the smelting/cooking process will start. It takes ten seconds for an item to get smelted or cooked in a furnace. All of the ready items will appear in the third box(at the right edge of the screen) and can be collected by tapping on it. Below there are pictures showing how the furnace works.</string>
	<string name="howtosmelt_text4080">In this picture, the fuel box is selected, and in the inventory at the left, you can see that the available fuel gets highlighted, in this case there\'s only coal available</string>
	<string name="howtosmelt_text5080">In this picture, the upper box is selected, and now you can see all of the cookable/smeltable items in your inventory highlighted. Note that once you have an item in both boxes, the smelting process will begin.</string>
	<string name="howtosmelt_text6080">Here you can see the smelting in action.</string>
	<string name="typerequired">Type in the required information!</string>
	<string name="yes">Yes</string>
	<string name="no">No</string>
	<string name="customrom">Do you have a custom ROM in your device?</string>
	<string name="typerom">What is your ROM?</string>
	<string name="typerequiredplusrom">Type in the required information! Also type in the details of your custom ROM!</string>
	<string name="musttyperom">Type in the details of your ROM!</string>
	<string name="selratingmethod">Select your rating method</string>
	<string name="playrating">Rate on Google Play Store</string>
	<string name="mailrating">Rate through Email</string>
	<string name="inputlanguage">Type your answers in english or finnish!</string>

</resources>
